<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Sherif Ahmed</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Sherif Ahmed</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.151.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CourseTA</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/courseta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/courseta/</guid>
      <description>An agent-based educational system using FastAPI, LangChain, and LangGraph in a microservice architecture. Implemented real-time async endpoints, integrated Whisper for audio/video transcription, and PyMuPDF for PDF parsing. Built a RAG-based QA pipeline with embedding-based retrieval, and AI agents for question generation, summarization, and feedback refinement. Optimized for scalable human-in-the-loop workflows and efficient content transformation across diverse formats.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Group Activity Recognition</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/group-activity-recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/group-activity-recognition/</guid>
      <description>A modern implementation implemented a Hierarchical Deep Temporal Model for Group Activity Recognition, based on the CVPR 2016 paper. Achieved 93% accuracy using a two-stage LSTM architecture to recognize multi-person activities. Conducted ablation studies to evaluate the contributions of various model components and compared performance against 8 baseline models.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relational Group Activity Recognition</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/rgar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/rgar/</guid>
      <description>Implemented a Hierarchical Relational Network architecture for Group Activity Recognition and Retrieval, based on the ECCV 2018 paper. This implementation models inter-person relations and hierarchical temporal dynamics using Relational Layer (Graph Relational Layer). Ablation experiments were conducted to assess the impact of relation modeling, attention mechanisms (Graph Attention Operator), and hierarchical layers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ImgCap</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/imacap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/imacap/</guid>
      <description>ImgCap is an image captioning model designed to automatically generate descriptive captions for images. It has two versions one based on a CNN-LSTM architecture, and the other an enhanced version that integrates a CNN-LSTM with an Attention mechanism. To further enhance the quality and coherence of generated captions, beam search is implemented during the inference stage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Credit Card Fraud Detection</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/credit-card-fraud-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/credit-card-fraud-detection/</guid>
      <description>Credit card fraud detection project using a highly unbalanced Kaggle dataset of 284,807 transactions with only 492 frauds. To address the imbalance the project implements a voting classifier and a neural network with focal loss in PyTorch achieving an F1 score of 86% and a PR AUC of 85%</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tennis Analysis System</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/tennis-analysis-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/tennis-analysis-system/</guid>
      <description>Tennis-Analysis-System is a system that analyzes tennis matches and provides player statistics and mini court visualizations.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
